WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I was born in space.
I've never felt the sun on my face
Or breathed real air
or floated in the water.
None of us have.
For 3 generations, the
Ark has kept what's left
of the human race alive,
but now our home is dying,
and we are the last hope of mankind,
100 prisoners sent on a desperate mission
to the ground.
Each of us is here
because we broke the law.
On the ground, there is no law.
All we have to do is survive,
but we will be tested by the Earth,
by the secrets it hides,
and most of all by each other.
Previously on "The 100."
We know they've landed,
but communications are down.
This wristband transmits
your vital signs to the Ark.
Take them off, and Ark
will think we're dying.
- That's the point.
- They've dumped you down here
like lab rats to die,
so why are you helping them?
Chancellor's been shot.
We have I.D.ed the
shooter... Bellamy Blake.
I did something they will kill
me for when they come down.
Do you see that peak over there?
That's Mount Weather.
There's a radiation-soaked
forest between us
- and our next meal.
- We did it!
We are not alone.
Clarke! Come on.
Monty.
- Come on!
- We got to go!
Monty, get up!
Who are they?
What are they?
We are so screwed.
Jasper. He's alive.
Clarke, wait. Wait!
Wait. Stay out of the trees.
He was right there.
No. Where is he?
They took him.
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -
- Talk to me, Jackson.
- Rumors are spreading.
Witnesses saw a dropship launch.
It's only a matter of time
till the people figure out
that we sent the hundred to the ground.
Let the council worry about the people.
I need you focused on reestablishing
communication with those kids.
How many dark tiles?
23. We've been losing them at
a steady rate all day.
Abby, these are different.
Vital signs spike for a longer duration
before flat line; It
looks like a pain response.
This is what we'd expect to
see with exposure to radiation.
I know what it looks like, Jackson,
but there's another explanation.
We just haven't found it yet.
Chancellor on deck.
My son.
- We sent them down to die.
- No.
We sent them down to live...
To go to Earth to see if it was
survivable so that all of us could live.
Abby, stop.
I know this is hard,
but we don't have time for false hope.
This space station is dying,
and Earth is not survivable.
That is what the wristbands are telling us.
We don't know what they're telling us yet.
Thelonious,
listen to me.
Please trust me.
For all we know, those kids
could be perfectly fine,
including Wells.
Get him!
Way to go!
I got it, I got it!
Dude, get back here!
- Move!
- Take it!
See? Ha ha!
Hey, where'd you get the clothes?
Buried the two kids who
died during the landing.
Smart. You know, I'll take it from here.
There's always a market for...
We share based on need,
just like back home.
You still don't get it, do you, Chancellor?
This is home now.
Your father's rules no longer apply.
Oh, no, no, Atom. Atom, hold up.
You want it back? Take it.
Get those boots!
Is this what you want? Chaos?
What's wrong with a little chaos?
Bellamy.
Check it out. We want the Ark to think
that the ground is killing us, right?
Figure it'll look better if
we suffer a little bit first.
Let her go!
You can stop this.
Stop this?
I'm just getting started.
Fight!
Don't you see you can't control this?
You're dead.
Wait.
Fair fight.
Aah!
This is for my father!
Drop it!
Wells!
Let him go!
Whoa. Hey!
Enough, Murphy.
Octavia. Are you all right?
Yeah.
Where's the food?
We didn't make it to Mount Weather.
What the hell happened out there?
We were attacked.
Attacked? By what?
Not what. Who.
It turns out, when the last man
from the ground died on the Ark,
he wasn't the last grounder.
It's true.
Everything we thought we knew
about the ground is wrong.
There are people here,
survivors.
The good news is, that
means we can survive.
Radiation won't kill us.
Yeah, the bad news is the grounders will.
Where's the kid with the goggles?
Jasper was hit.
They took him.
Where is your wristband?
Ask him.
How many?
24 and counting.
You idiots.
Life support on the Ark is failing.
That's why they brought us down here.
They need to know the
ground is survivable again,
and we need their help
against whoever is out there.
If you take off your wristbands,
you're not just killing them.
You're killing us!
We're stronger than you think.
Don't listen to her.
She's one of the privileged.
If they come down, she'll have it good.
How many of you can say the same?
We can take care of ourselves.
That wristband on your arm?
It makes you a prisoner.
We are not prisoners anymore!
They say they'll forgive your crimes.
I say you're not criminals!
You're fighters, survivors!
The grounders should worry about us!
- Yeah!
What do we do now?
Now we go after Jasper.
Why are you here, Abby?
We both know that you could have
sent an apprentice to do this.
Kane's planning a secret council meeting
to vote on the culling.
I need to know where you stand.
I don't have a vote. You know that.
They listen to you, Thelonious.
Well, you don't.
I do when you agree with me.
Now, Abby, the CO2 scrubbers
are already failing.
The symptoms of oxygen
deprivation are everywhere,
and worst of all in the
children; They'll die first.
- You don't have to tell me that.
- Obviously I do.
Unless we act to reduce the population,
everyone on-board this space
station will be dead in 4 months.
We have acted. We put a
hundred kids on the ground.
We need to give them time...
There are 76 kids on the ground, Abby.
24 of them,
including my son, are already dead.
- I don't think so.
- But you have no proof.
Please... Stop.
I understand your need
to have hope for Clarke,
but I am the Chancellor of the Ark,
and hope isn't enough.
Not when the end of the
human race is at stake.
You wanted to see me?
Hope is everything,
and the Chancellor that I voted for,
he knew that.
I'm done here.
Stop studying me, Kane.
Who shot me?
Bellamy Blake,
a janitor from factory station.
He stowed away on the dropship.
We're still investigating who helped him.
Who benefits most from my death?
If you have something to say, just say it.
You rushed to execute the
woman who saved my life,
and if I were dead, you
would be Chancellor now
and Abby wouldn't be here to oppose you.
I followed the law. I did my job.
You were the acting Chancellor...
And this job requires more
than simply following the law.
It requires knowing when not to.
I had nothing to do with
the attempt on your life,
but I'm not surprised that it happened.
You're too weak to do
what now has to be done,
and I'm not the only one who knows it.
There you are.
When my father said they didn't
leave us anything, he really meant it.
It's just a scratch.
You're making friends fast.
Keep it covered. It could get infected.
Nice pack.
Yeah, seat belts and insulation.
I also packed part of the parachute,
figured we could use it
to carry out Jasper.
Good. Give it to someone else.
- You're not coming with us.
- My ankle's fine.
It's not your ankle, Wells, it's you.
You came back for
reinforcements. I'm gonna help.
Clarke, he's right. We need him.
So far no one else has volunteered.
I'm sorry, Monty, but
you're not going, either.
Like hell I'm not. Jasper's my best friend.
You're too important.
You were raised on farm station
and recruited by engineering.
- So?
- So food and communication.
What's up here, it's gonna save us all.
You figure out how to talk to the
Ark and I'll bring Jasper back.
Hey. You ready?
I'm not going anywhere, and
neither should any of you.
That spear was thrown with
pinpoint accuracy from 300 feet.
- So what, we let Jasper die?
- That's not gonna happen.
Spacewalker?
What a joke.
You think you're such an adventurer.
You're really just a coward.
It's not an adventure, Clarke,
it's a suicide mission.
Build a wall.
Use the fallen trees.
I'll watch out for her.
Jasper looked up to you.
- What the hell was it?
- I don't know.
The others said it
looked like a giant snake.
You could have been killed.
She would have been if Jasper
didn't jump in to pull her out.
You guys leaving? I'm coming, too.
No, no. No way. Not again.
He's right. Your leg's
just gonna slow us down.
I'm here for you.
Clarke, what are you doing?
I hear you have a gun.
Good. Follow me.
And why would I do that?
Because you want them to follow you,
and right now, they're thinking
only one of us is scared.
Murphy.
Come with me. Atom?
My sister doesn't leave
this camp. Is that clear?
I don't need a babysitter.
Anybody touches her, they answer to me.
Let's go.
You're staying here.
I'm gonna make your life a living hell.
Those guys aren't just bullies, Clarke.
They're dangerous criminals.
I'm counting on it.
Since when are we in the
rescuing business, huh?
The Ark thinks the prince is dead.
Once they think the princess
is, too, they'll never come down.
I'm getting that wristband,
even if I have to cut
off her hand to do it.
Damn it, Raven.
Wait for pressurization.
Sorry, boys. Places to go.
Did anyone notice there's
no damage to "B" dock?
"B" dock's restricted. You know that.
What, are they gonna float me for looking?
Guys, come on.
An exodus ship was launched.
You're not curious about that?
It was not launched. It was ejected.
According to engineering,
a routine maintenance
accident forced them to eject.
A maintenance accident that
didn't cause any damage?
That's a lie and you know it.
Fine. Well, if that doesn't stir your tank,
how about this?
Why would they build a
dropship in the first place?
Just slow down, all right?
We need to check your vitals.
I'll save you the trouble.
I feel good.
Prison visiting day. Tell
lover boy I'll pay him
the two days' rations I
owe him when he gets out.
It was 3 days. Hey, stash my gear.
I'll come back for it later.
Ok, Raven, stop.
Lockup's been quarantined.
There's some kind of a virus.
There's no visitation for
at least two months. Sorry.
Hey, I saw that. You cheated.
Hey, guys, the wall's
not gonna build itself.
Walls won't stop what's
out there. We need weapons.
So build weapons. Look...
Your brother wasn't kidding
about that. He'll hurt them.
Come on. We were just talking.
You're too hot to be my brother's bitch.
- I'm no one's bitch.
- Mmm. Good.
Then prove it.
Come with me.
- Hey. Oof!
- Get out of here.
Nobody's bitch, huh?
Maybe one of these days you'll
realize you can't control me.
You know, that guy you with?
Did you know he was in for murder?
You want to know something funny?
I'm actually protecting him from you.
Hey, hey, hey, hey! What are you doing?!
Consider yourself controlled.
Is this all you got? They
locked me under the floor
for 16 years just for being born!
This is nothing.
Ahem. You want to keep it down?
I'm trying to concentrate.
Attention. The mess hall will be closed
from 2100 hours to 0800 hours
for maintenance.
Attention.
The mess hall will be
closed from 2100 hours...
Abby...
Kane's lobbying for votes.
We should, too.
We'll have our chance at the briefing.
Excuse me! Dr. Griffin.
I have a question about the quarantine.
My boyfriend's in lockup.
I went to go see him.
Instead, I saw an open air duct.
Now, if there really was a virus,
wouldn't you move to contain the airflow?
The virus isn't airborne.
That's why the ducts are open.
Can you tell me if he's ok?
I can't. I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
First the dropship, now this.
The council's hiding something,
and I'm gonna find out what it is.
Ballsy kid.
Yeah.
Reminds me of someone.
Hey, hold up.
What's the rush?
You don't survive a
spear through the heart.
Put the gun away, Bellamy.
Well, why don't you do
something about it, huh?
Jasper screamed when they moved him.
If the spear struck his heart,
he'd have died instantly.
It doesn't mean we have time to waste.
As soon as you take this
wristband off, we can go.
The only way the Ark is gonna
think I'm dead is if I'm dead.
Got it?
Brave princess.
Hey, why don't you find your own nickname?
You call this a rescue party?
Got to split up, cover more ground.
Clarke, come with me.
Better late than never.
I like to think so.
Guess we got more in common
than meets the eye, huh?
We have nothing in common.
No?
Both came down here to
protect someone we love.
Your secret's safe with me.
'Course, for you it's worse.
With Finn around,
Clarke doesn't even see you.
It's like you're not even here.
He may not be my real brother...
... But he's always been there.
Every memory I have, there's Jasper.
I should be out there.
You're not gonna cry, are you?
Shut up.
You sure about this?
Your brother won't approve
of you helping us contact the Ark.
He's not my keeper.
Let's just do this. Let's do it.
Aah!
Ow!
- Son of a...
- Sorry.
- Dead.
- Oh.
Damn it.
If we can't even take it off,
how do you expect to turn it into a radio?
Go on.
I'll be fine. Work to do.
Hey, Monty?
Jasper would understand why you stayed.
How is someone raised beneath
the floor not a total basket case?
Who says I'm not?
It's because he loves you.
Your brother?
You're not a basket case
because you were loved.
Yeah, I'm a lucky girl.
I'm not saying I had it worse than
you, Octavia, because I didn't.
But you have someone who
would do anything for you.
I envy that.
I've been thinking about Mount Weather.
How come they didn't attack
until Jasper crossed the river?
It's not like we were being quiet
and they didn't know we were there.
They waited for us to cross.
The river's a boundary.
Which means Mount Weather is off limits.
How are we gonna get those supplies?
What are we gonna do for food?
Wow.
Well, at least we don't
have to worry about water.
Oh, yeah.
Come on, Finn. We don't have time for this.
Clarke, we've been hiking for hours.
We need to take a break.
I'll take a break when we find Jasper.
Come on.
No, no. Finn! Don't!
Damn it, Finn!
Oh, wow. Ok.
- Maybe just a minute.
- Yeah.
I think I know why you're so
hell-bent on finding Jasper,
why you're always taking
care of everybody else.
Now you sound like my mother.
No. Go on. This should be good.
The delinquent psychiatrist.
You couldn't save your father.
Jasper. He was here.
We should get the others.
We're close.
Abby, we have to stop.
The council vote's in 30 minutes.
Then we have 30 minutes.
- Anything from engineering?
- Nothing good.
According to Sinclair, even if we
sent a signal down, the wristbands
weren't designed to receive, so
the kids wouldn't even hear it.
There's got to be something
we missed, something
that we haven't thought of.
Great. What's falling apart now?
Hey! Hey!
Apparently you have a thing for air ducts.
I'll call security.
They're not dying.
What are you talking about?
All that's being sent from the ground?
Transmitted by these.
They're taking them off.
What? Why would they do
something so reckless?
Because we told them not to.
Hello, beautiful.
Hey, where are you going?
It's ok.
We've got nothing but time.
Hey, how do we know this is the right way?
We don't. Spacewalker
thinks he's a tracker.
It's called "cutting sign."
Fourth-year earth skills. He's good.
You want to keep it down or should
I paint a target on your backs?
See? You're invisible.
What the hell was that?
Now would be a good time
to take out that gun.
Jasper.
- Oh, my God.
- Clarke, be careful.
Jasper?
What the hell is this?
Clarke! Get her up!
Pull her up! Pull her
up! Get her! Pull her up!
- You ok?
- Yeah.
We need to get him down.
I'll climb up there and cut the vines.
- Yeah, yeah, I'm with you.
- No. Stay with Clarke.
And watch him.
You. Let's go.
There's a poultice on his wound.
Medicine? Why would they save his life
just to string him up as live bait?
Maybe what they're trying to catch
likes its dinner to be breathing.
Maybe what they're trying to catch is us.
Data indicates that the
violent criminals in the group
are 8 times more likely
to have terminated signals.
We believe that this means that the kids
are taking off the wristbands by choice.
So how do you explain Wells?
Kane is right.
My son would... Never take
his wristband off voluntarily.
Both our children have done things
that we could never have predicted.
The point holds.
These children need more time.
We don't have time.
Engineering needs 6 months
to fix life support,
and we'll be out of oxygen in 4.
Nobody wants to do this, but the
inescapable fact is that for every day
we delay, 10 more people
will need to be sacrificed.
So today it's 209, tomorrow it's 219.
The day after that is 229.
We're the ones who need more time.
I move that we vote now.
- I second that.
- Very well.
The matter before us requires
a 4-vote majority to pass.
A vote in favor is to vote to
cull 209 citizens of the Ark
from the supply grid in
order to extend life support
for those who remain by 6 months.
All those in favor?
Aye.
- Aye.
All those opposed?
- Nay.
3 votes to 3.
The Chancellor will break the tie.
We didn't ask for this.
Ours was to be a transitional generation...
Ensuring that 3 generations from now
mankind could go home.
But everything has changed,
and we will either be
the generation that sees
the human race return to Earth...
Or upon whose watch...
It finally ends.
My son is already down there.
I sent him.
And the truth is I don't know
if he is alive or dead.
But I still have hope.
How does the Chancellor vote?
I don't.
Sir, if you abstain, the vote ends in a tie
to be automatically
taken up again in 10 days.
That's 10 more dead for every day.
I ask again, how does the Chancellor vote?
The Chancellor abstains.
You have 10 days.
Hurry up, Murphy.
Be careful.
What the hell was that?
Grounders?
Bellamy, gun!
Now she sees you.
Did someone call for a mechanic?
You're the one who
called in the work order?
We need to talk.
Look, I told you I'm not
gonna say anything, ok?
I believe you, and you're not in trouble.
Follow me.
Not in trouble yet, you mean.
This level's off limits for people like me.
Not anymore.
You know that we sent the
hundred down to the ground.
What you don't know is why.
The Ark is dying, Raven.
Life support is on its last legs.
I have 10 days to prove
that Earth is survivable
or they're gonna start reducing population.
320 innocent people will be killed.
I don't get it.
Why are you telling me this?
I looked up your file.
You're the youngest zero-g mechanic
on the Ark in 50 years.
52, but... So what?
so...
You have 9 days to get this
ready so I can survive a drop.
God, what a piece of junk.
They must have found
this thing when they...
Salvaged MIR-3 in 2102.
You want me to get a
130-year-old escape pod
ready to stand up to
the inferno of re-entry
in 9 days?
Can you do it or not?
Hell, yes, I can do it,
but I'm going with you.
You're not the only one with
someone you love on the ground.
Those are my terms.
Take it or leave it.
All right. You can come with me.
You got yourself a mechanic.
They're back!
Over there.
- Is he...
- He's alive.
I need boiled water and
strips of cloth for bandage.
- Oh!
- Oh, ho ho!
- Who's hungry?!
- Yeah!
Bellamy! Whoo!
He's stable for now,
but without medicine...
They're taking off their
wristbands for food?
No way. I... I won't do it.
You don't have to.
Whoa, whoa. Wait, wait, wait.
What, you think you
play by different rules?
I thought there were no rules.
Hey.
Atom!
Come on. We're on first watch.
Guys, you're not just gonna leave me here.
No, Atom. I won't be disobeyed.
Guys!
Bellamy!
Guys! Bellamy!