WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I feel the sun on my face.
I see trees all around me,
scent of wildflowers on a breeze.
It's so beautiful.
In this moment, I'm not stranded in space.
It's been 97 years since
a nuclear apocalypse
killed everyone on Earth,
leaving the planet simmering in radiation.
Fortunately, there were survivors.
12 nations had operational space stations
at the time of the bombs.
There is now only The Ark,
one station forged from the many.
We're told the Earth
needs another 100 years
to become survivable again.
4 more space-locked generations,
and man can go home, back to the ground.
The ground, that's the
dream. This is reality.
Prisoner 319, face the wall.
Reality sucks.
What is this?
Quiet. Hold out your right arm.
No. No. It's not my time.
I don't turn 18 for another month.
Hold out your arm.
On The Ark, every crime,
no matter how small, is punishable by death
- unless you're under 18.
- Your watch.
No. It was my father's.
- Take it off.
- No.
- Hey!
Juvenile offenders get put here... lockup.
We call it the sky box.
Prisoner 319...
Clarke, stop. Wait here.
Mom? Mom, what's going on?
What is this?
Come on. Let's go.
They're killing us all, aren't they,
reducing population to make
more time for the rest of you?
Clarke, you are not being executed.
You're being sent to the ground,
all 100 of you.
What? But it's not safe.
No. No.
We get reviewed at 18.
The rules have changed.
This gives you a chance to live.
Your instincts will tell you
to take care of everybody else first,
just like your father, but be careful.
I can't lose you, too. I love you so much.
Earth, Clarke. You get to go to Earth.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -
Welcome back.
Look.
Wells, why the hell are you here?
When I found out they
were sending prisoners
to the ground, I got myself arrested.
I came for you.
What was that?
That was the atmosphere.
Prisoners of The Ark, hear me now.
You've been given a second chance,
and as your Chancellor, it
is my hope that you see this
as not just a chance for you,
but a chance for all of us,
indeed for mankind itself.
We have no idea what is
waiting for you down there.
If the odds of survival were better,
we would've sent others.
Frankly, we're sending
you because your crimes
have made you expendable.
Your dad is a dick, Wells.
Those crimes will be forgiven,
your records wiped clean.
I saw a ship launch not
more than 20 minutes ago.
Who was on it?
Was it the prisoners? They're just kids.
Are they going to Earth?
Has something changed?
Folks, as I said, at this time,
we cannot confirm or deny anything.
Come on, lady!
My son is on that ship.
The drop site has been chosen carefully.
Before the last war, Mount Weather
was a military base
built within a mountain.
It was to be stocked with
enough non-perishables
to sustain 300 people for up to two years.
Spacewalk bandit strikes again.
Go, Finn!
Check it out.
Your dad floated me, after all.
You should strap in before
the parachutes deploy.
Hey, you two, stay put if you want to live.
Mount Weather is life.
You must locate those supplies immediately.
Hey, you're the traitor who's
been in solitary for a year.
You're the idiot who
wasted a month of oxygen
on an illegal spacewalk.
But it was fun.
I'm Finn.
Your one responsibility is stay alive.
Stay in your seats.
Finn, are you ok?
Not now.
Total system failure,
that's what we're looking at.
All we know for sure is
that they were off course
when we lost contact, so...
Tell me about communications.
Other than the telemetry
from their wristbands,
we got nothing... no audio, no video,
no computer link.
Everything that we programmed in
to help them is gone.
They're on their own.
Retrorockets ought to have fired by now.
Ok. Everything on this ship
is 100 years old, right?
Just give it a second.
Clarke, there's something
I have to tell you.
I'm sorry I got your father arrested.
Don't you talk about my father.
Please, I can't die
knowing that you hate me.
They didn't arrest my father, Wells.
They executed him. I do hate you.
Listen.
No machine hum.
Whoa.
That's a first.
Finn, is he breathing?
The outer door is on the lower level.
- Let's go.
- No.
We can't just open the doors.
Hey, just back it up, guys.
Stop.
The air could be toxic.
If the air is toxic,
we're all dead, anyway.
Bellamy?
My God, look how big you are.
What the hell are you wearing,
a guard's uniform?
I borrowed it to get on the drop ship.
Someone has got to keep an eye on you.
Where's your wristband?
Do you mind?
I haven't seen my brother in a year.
No one has a brother.
That's Octavia Blake,
the girl they found hidden in the floor.
Octavia, Octavia, no.
Let's give them something else
to remember you by.
Yeah? Like what?
Like being the first person
on the ground in 100 years.
We're back, bitches!
Why so serious, princess?
It's not like we died in a fiery explosion.
Try telling that to the two guys
who tried to follow you out of their seats.
You don't like being called princess,
do you, princess?
Do you see that peak over there?
Yeah.
Mount Weather.
There's a radiation-soaked forest
between us and our next meal.
They dropped us on the wrong damn mountain.
There it is.
We know they've landed,
but communications are down,
which means we're still blind
to conditions on the ground.
Thanks to Abby's wristbands,
at least we know how those conditions
affect the human body, which is
more than we've had for 100 years.
So nice work.
Now, what are they telling us?
Two dead kids, dark tiles.
Dr. Jackson, please share our theory
with Councilor Kane.
Of course.
Granted, they've only been
on the ground for 7 minutes,
but as of now, we believe the fatalities
are due to the landing,
not radiation levels.
Both boys died at the same time
that we lost contact with the drop ship.
- Rough landing? That's your theory?
- The dots connect.
Would you agree that if it was radiation,
we'd see fatalities
climb fairly quickly now?
Because I'm noticing a
lot of red on that board.
Spiking vital signs, two possibilities...
one, injuries sustained during landing.
And the other?
They're excited to be there.
We got problems.
The communications system is dead.
I went to the roof.
A dozen panels are missing.
Heat fried the wires.
Well, all that matters right
now is getting to Mount Weather.
See? Look.
This is us.
This is where we need to
get to if we want to survive.
Where'd you learn to do that?
Your father.
Ah, cool, a map.
They got a bar in this
town? I'll buy you a beer.
You mind?
Hey, hey, hey,
hands off of him. He's with us.
Relax.
We're just trying to
figure out where we are.
We're on the ground. That
not good enough for you?
We need to find Mount Weather.
You heard my father's message.
That has to be our first priority.
Screw your father.
What, you think you're in charge here,
you and your little princess?
Do you think we care who's in charge?
We need to get to Mount Weather
not because the Chancellor said so,
but because the longer we wait,
the hungrier we'll get
and the harder this'll be.
How long do you think we'll
last without those supplies?
We're looking at a 20-mile trek, ok?
So if we want to get there before dark,
we need to leave now.
I got a better idea.
You two go, find it for us.
Let the privileged do the
hard work for a change.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
You're not listening. We all need to go.
Look at this, everybody...
the Chancellor of Earth.
Think that's funny?
- Uh!
- Wells.
Yeah. Come on. Get him.
No, but that was. All right.
What you gonna do now, Wells?
Come on. Come on.
Kid's got one leg.
How about you wait until it's a fair fight?
Hey, spacewalker,
rescue me next.
What? He's cute.
He's a criminal.
They're all criminals.
Look, O. I came down here to protect you.
I don't need protecting.
I have been locked up one way
or another all my life.
I am done following orders.
I need to have fun, Bell.
I need to just do something crazy
just because I can, and no one,
including you, is gonna stop me.
I can't stay with them, O.
Now what are you talking about?
Go find something.
I did something, ok,
to get on the drop ship,
something that they will kill me for
when they come down.
I can't say what it is just yet,
but you have to trust me.
You do still trust me, don't you?
Yeah.
So Mount Weather. When do we leave?
Right now.
We'll be back tomorrow with food.
How are the two of you gonna carry
enough food for 100?
4 of us. Can we go now?
Sounds like a party. Make it 5.
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
- Going for a walk.
- Hey,
were you trying to take this off?
Yeah. So?
So this wristband transmits
your vital signs to The Ark.
Take it off, and they'll think you're dead.
Should I care?
Well, I don't know.
Do you want the people you
love to think you're dead?
Do you want them to follow
you down here in two months?
Because they won't if
they think we're dying.
Ok.
Now let's go.
Go on.
You shouldn't have come here, Wells.
Before you get any ideas, Finn is mine.
Before you get any ideas, I don't care.
Hey, darling, how's Clarke?
Her vital signs are strong,
blood sugar is low.
She hasn't eaten.
This is Dr. Griffin.
On my way.
Jackson, put it out there we need blood...
"A" neg. And a lot of it...
and then get your ass to the O.R.
Abby, what's wrong?
The Chancellor has been shot.
Now, that, my friend, is game.
That, my friend, is poison sumac.
What? It is?
The flowers aren't poisonous.
They're medicinal, calming, actually.
His family grows all the
pharmaceuticals on The Ark.
Hey, guys, would you try to keep up?
Come on, Clarke. How do
you block all this out?
Well, it's simple.
I wonder, "why haven't
we seen any animals?"
Maybe it's because there are none.
Maybe we've already been exposed
to enough radiation to kill us.
Sure is pretty, though. Come on.
Someone should slip her some poison sumac.
I got to know what you
two did to get busted.
Sumac is not the only herb in the garden,
if you know what I mean.
Someone forget to replace what we took.
Someone has apologized, like, 1,000 times.
How about you, Octavia?
What'd they get you for?
Being born.
That is so not game.
No animals, huh?
Chancellor has lost a lot of blood.
If only they found him sooner, damn it.
He's waking up.
Increase the anesthesia.
We used way too much blood and anesthesia.
We're way over the line.
Your Chancellor is going into shock.
You're asking me to break the law.
Fine. I'll do it myself.
Let them come after me.
Excuse me, sir.
You asked to be notified if there was news.
The Chancellor is still in surgery,
but we have I.D.ed the shooter.
Bellamy Blake is the only person
on The Ark unaccounted for.
Who is he?
He's no one, a janitor.
We're still working up a profile,
but his motive for going to Earth is clear.
Sister. I remember.
Her mother kept her
hidden for almost 16 years,
nearly a record.
What is it, Commander Shumway. Spit it out.
We could start now.
As Chancellor pro tempore,
you can give the order
to start reducing the population.
Not yet.
Sir, we're wasting time.
Removing the 100 from the population
only buys us another month.
Engineering needs more than
that to fix those systems,
if they can fix them at all.
You have my answer, Commander. Enough.
If we're gonna kill
hundreds of innocent people,
we're gonna do it by the book.
Is that clear?
In the meantime, I want to know who helped
this janitor get on that drop ship
because he sure as hell
didn't do it by himself.
Seems we have a traitor
in our midst, Commander,
and the 100 have an assassin in theirs.
Find any water yet?
No, not yet, but...
I'm going back out if you want to come.
You know, my father, he begged for mercy
in the airlock chamber when
your father floated him.
You spelled "die" wrong, geniuses.
If you're gonna kill someone,
it's probably best not to announce it.
You're not really a member
of the guard, are you?
No. The real guard will be
here soon unless we stop it.
You don't actually think they're
gonna forgive your crimes.
Even if they do, then what?
Guys like us, we're gonna
become model citizens now,
get jobs, if we're lucky,
- maybe pick up their trash?
- You got a point?
No. I got a question.
They locked you up, dumped you down here
like lab rats to die.
So why are you helping them?
The hell we are.
You're wearing those bracelets, aren't you?
Right now, those things are telling them
whether or not it's safe to follow us down.
Ok. You said we could stop it. How?
Take them off.
The Ark will think you're dead,
that it's not safe to follow.
You follow?
Right, and if we do,
I mean, what's in it for us?
Someone has got to help me run things.
Hey, Ab. How's the Chancellor doing?
Ask me again if he makes
it through the night.
Who else did we lose?
Murphy and Mbege, both named John.
Neither was injured during landing.
I concur. Something else killed these two.
One second, they were fine,
- and the next, bang.
- Then it isn't radiation.
Come on, Abby.
Wishful thinking isn't good science.
It's not wishful thinking.
One second, fine, the next, bang
isn't how exposure to radiation presents.
Well, it could be if
there was enough of it.
If there was enough of it,
they would all be dead.
Please let me be right.
Hey, you know what I'd like to know?
Why send us down today after 97 years?
What changed?
Who cares? I'm just glad they did.
I woke up rotting in a cell,
and now I'm spinning in a forest.
Maybe they found something on a satellite,
you know, like an old
weather satellite or...
It wasn't a satellite.
The Ark is dying.
At the current population level,
there's roughly 3 months left
of life support, maybe
4 now that we're gone.
So that was the secret
they locked you up to keep,
why the kept you in solitary,
floated your old man?
My father was the engineer
who discovered the flaw.
He thought the people had a right to know.
The council disagreed. My mother disagreed.
They were afraid it would cause a panic.
We were gonna go public,
anyway, when Wells...
What, turned in your dad?
Anyway, the guard showed
up before we could.
That's why today.
That's why it was worth the risk.
Even if we all die, at least
they bought themselves more time.
They're gonna kill more
people, aren't they?
Good. After what they did to me,
I say, float them all.
You don't mean that.
We have to warn them.
That's what my father said.
Oh, damn, I love Earth.
Oh! Holy...
Octavia, what the hell are you doing?
Octavia...
I can't swim.
I know, but we can stand. Ha ha ha!
Wait. There's not supposed
to be a river here.
Well, there is.
So take off your damn clothes.
Octavia, get out of the water.
Get out of the water now!
Octavia!
No.
What the hell is that? We have to help her.
- What are you gonna do?
- Try not to get eaten.
No. Wait.
If we distract it, it
might let her go. Help me.
No!
It worked. It let her go.
Can you get to the shore now?
I got you.
It's coming back.
It's headed right for you, guys.
Come on. Come on. Keep going.
Ok.
Thank you. Thank you.
You're gonna be ok.
Note to self...
next time, save the girl.
Yeah. Go on, baby.
Yeah. Keep going.
Who's next?
What the hell are you doing?
We're liberating ourselves.
What does it look like?
It looks like you're
trying to get us all killed.
The communication system is dead.
These wristbands are all we got.
Take them off, and The
Ark will think we're dying,
that it's not safe for them to follow.
That's the point, Chancellor.
We can take care of ourselves, can't we?
Yeah!
You think this is a game?
Those aren't just our friends
and our parents up there.
They're our farmers, our
doctors, our engineers.
I don't care what he tells you.
We won't survive here on our own...
and besides, if it really is safe,
how could you not want the rest
of our people to come down?
My people already are down.
Those people locked my people up.
Those people killed my mother for the crime
of having a second child.
Your father did that.
- My father didn't write the laws.
- No.
He enforced them,
but not anymore,
not here.
Here, there are no laws.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Cool.
Here, we do whatever the hell we want
whenever the hell we want.
Now, you don't have to like it, Wells.
You can even try to stop it or change it,
kill me.
You know why?
Whatever the hell we want.
Whatever the hell we want!
♪ whatever the hell we want ♪
Rain! Real rain!
Check it out!
It's water!
We need to collect this.
Whatever the hell you want.
10 more, one after the next.
Abby, look at plasma osmolarity.
It's going up across the board.
They found water.
Councilor Abigail Griffin,
you're under arrest
for exceeding the maximum medical
supplies allowed for a patient.
Sorry this has to be public.
The policy in these
matters is very clear...
no special treatment.
- How much blood did you use, Abby?
- Don't answer that.
I used whatever it took.
Breaking the law to keep
you from becoming Chancellor
was the easiest decision I've ever made.
In that case,
given your confession,
in my role as Chancellor pro tempore,
you leave me no choice
but to find you guilty.
We always have a choice, Kane.
You chose to press
charges against my husband,
your friend, even though you knew
he would get floated for it.
You chose to include my
daughter in those charges,
and now you're choosing this.
Hiding behind the law
absolves you of nothing.
Be that as it may, in accordance
with penal code one,
because all crimes
committed by those
above the age of maturity
are capital crimes,
you are hereby sentenced to death.
Execution is set for the morning,
and I choose at every turn
and at any cost
to make sure
that the human race stays alive.
That's the difference between us, Kane.
I choose to make sure
that we deserve to stay alive.
Pretty cool, huh?
Did you go to the river?
Figured it was worth
losing a finger or two.
Here.
You call that a sip?
You think this means we're all
gonna grow two heads?
What do you know? She can laugh.
Come on. You have to see this.
That's a toe.
Plus, near as I can tell,
whatever it is, it's walking on two feet.
My Guess... monkeys.
I'm sorry. It's just, according
to everything I've read,
there were no bipedal
animals anywhere near here,
certainly not monkeys.
Right. You read anything about
glow-in-the-dark forests
or man-eating snakes?
Are you out of your mind?
You can't just kill everyone
who disagrees with you.
Now, you all think I'm a bad guy,
but I'm the only one who's willing to do
what it takes to save us.
She's my best friend.
So what do you want me to say,
I'm sorry?
I'm not.
Friendship is a luxury we can't afford,
and if I have to take us
down to a cosmic Adam and Eve,
I will do it.
Please, show mercy,
if not for Abby, then for me.
We can't afford mercy, either.
That's far enough.
I don't want to shoot you, Wells...
hell, I like you...
but I do need them
to think that you're dead.
Why? Why are you doing this, for real,
not some crap about getting to do
what you want to do?
I have my reasons. I also have the gun.
So I ask the questions,
and the question is,
why aren't you helping me?
You dad banished you, Wells, and yet
here you are, still doing his bidding,
following the rules.
Aren't you tired of always doing
what's expected of you?
Stand up to him.
Take off that wristband,
and you'll be amazed
at how good it feels.
No.
Never. Not gonna happen.
Is that clear enough for you?
Yeah. It is.
I'm sorry it had to be this way.
No! No! Get off of me! No!
Get him down. Put him down.
No! Come on, man. Let me go.
Get it. Do it.
No! Don't do this! Don't do this! No. No!
Come on, man. Aah!
Dr. Griffin, it's time.
Callie.
That's enough.
Watch out for Clarke for me.
Ok.
Jackson, use the wristbands.
There may be a way to
reverse-engineer them
for communication.
Talk to Sinclair in engineering.
Nod if you understand.
Stop.
Dr. Griffin is pardoned.
I'll deal with you later.
Open the door.
I spent 12 hours putting
those intestines back together.
Get him back to bed now.
Tell me about the 100.
Did they make it?
You wanted to go first. Now quit stalling.
Mount weather awaits.
Just hang on till the apogee,
and you'll be fine.
The apogee like the Indians, right?
Apogee, not apache.
He knows. Today, Finn.
Aye, aye, captain. See
you on the other side.
- Wait.
- What?
Let me.
I can do it.
Knew there was a badass in there somewhere.
Hey, it's ok to be afraid, Jasper.
The trick is not fighting it.
See you on the other side. Ha ha!
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! Yeah!
We are apogee!
Yeah!
Yes! Whoo!
Yeah! Whoo!
You did it, Jasper!
Whoo! Yeah!
Let's go, princess.
You're up.
Come on, Clarke! You got this!
Whoo! Apogee!
We did it!
Mount weather! Whoo! Whoo!
Yes!
Yeah, Jasper!
Jasper.
Come on. Come on. Come on. Jasper!
Jasper! No. Come on.
Get down. Get down.
Come on.
We're not alone.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -