WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I was born in space.
I've never felt the sun on my face
or breathed real air
or floated in the water.
None of us have. For 3 generations,
The Ark has kept what's
left of the human race alive,
but now our home is dying, and we
are the last hope of mankind.
100 prisoners sent on a
desperate mission to the ground.
Each of us is here
because we broke the law.
On the ground, there is no law.
All we have to do is survive.
But we will be tested,
by the Earth, by the secrets it hides,
and most of all, by each other.
Previously on The 100...
These children need more time.
We don't have time.
Engineering needs 6 months
to fix life support, or
we'll be out of oxygen in 4.
No matter what happens,
you launch that pod.
The second you find those
kids, you radio back.
300 innocent people will die if you don't.
Sir... a pod launched.
Hey.
Hi.
It's almost dawn.
We should probably get going.
Can't just lie around in bed all day.
Or we could just lie around in bed all day.
Finn... you know that last night wasn't
just about needing someone.
I needed you.
I wanted it to be you.
You understand that, right?
Sure.
And I should probably tell you that
last night, for me,
wasn't really about you.
I just wanted to have my first Earth sex.
You were around. Passably cute.
Jackass.
Prisoner. Step to the rear of the cell.
Have we heard from Raven?
You can leave us alone, Sergeant.
Sir.
Has Raven started her descent?
Environmental numbers?
As of this morning.
Oxygen is down 16%.
Co2 and methane are heading to red levels.
Our projections said that
we wouldn't be critical
for another 3 months.
Your husband's projections were wrong.
The council has granted you
work release pending review.
Medical is overwhelmed.
Dizziness, fatigue, vision problems.
It's pulmonary toxicity.
I know how they feel.
The prison section has been
on half-air since midnight.
No.
I'm not gonna take more than my share.
We start choosing who gets extra o2,
and we're one step closer
to choosing who lives and who dies.
Abby... The council approved Kane's
population reduction plan 3 hours ago.
You voted without me.
We followed the rules of order.
It wouldn't have mattered.
Their approval was unanimous.
We start in 12 hours.
How many?
320 people will be excised from the grid.
No, murdered, Thelonious.
320 people will be murdered.
We need to wait for Raven to report back.
Look at those numbers.
Every hour that passes, we
put more people in danger.
She risked her life for those people.
No, you risked her life.
When you let her believe that loving a boy
somehow meant trusting her life
in a 100-year-old metal coffin.
And that trust is going to kill her.
Another child dead,
just like all the others,
just like our own.
Take this. People are suffering.
You can help.
Raven will make it to
Earth. I know she will.
Godspeed to her.
Ok. RCS valve... open.
RCS thrust pressure good.
Ahh. Attitude... good.
Heat shield... good.
Ok. Ahh.
Don't blow up.
Uhh!
It's so quiet.
Hey, where'd you get that shirt?
Oh. Well, there were more than just
art supplies in the bunker, Finn.
We should share.
If we brought the stuff back,
then they'd know that we found someplace
and where would we go next time
someone pulls a Murphy and goes ballistic?
Yeah.
I wanted it to be you, too.
Finn. Look.
A shooting star.
You should make a wish.
Why?
It's a thing people used
to do a long time ago.
I read about it.
But it's just a rock
burning up in the atmosphere.
Why would that make your wish come true?
All right... romance killer.
Finn, that's not a shooting star.
Check it out.
Bellamy! Get out here!
There!
They're coming to help us.
Now we can kick some grounder ass.
- Ha ha!
- Yeah!
Please tell me they
brought down some shampoo.
We should stop at camp.
Get some gear. Weapons.
They send some down?
It's too small to be a dropship.
I'm thinking cargo pod.
No. They wouldn't arm
a bunch of juvenile delinquents.
It's probably nutrition packs,
medical supplies.
There'd be a radio.
We can talk to The Ark.
That is if the radio
wasn't fried in the landing.
We're not alone down here anymore.
That's a good thing.
Yeah, not for Wells or Charlotte or Atom.
Nobody thought any of us would survive.
But we did.
You should take a minute
to appreciate that.
Ok. Minute's done.
If it cleared the ridge,
it's probably near the lake.
We should get moving. Everyone's ready.
No one's going anywhere.
Not while it's dark. It isn't safe.
We'll head out at first
light. Pass the word.
Everyone for 100 miles
saw this thing come down.
What if the grounders get to it first?
Bell, we should go now.
I said we wait until sunrise.
Blue triangle. Orange
square. Yellow triangle.
Green circle. A little smooshed.
It's an oval.
Thanks, dad. I forget,
whose eyes are they testing?
Ok, Reese.
Now the other eye.
Nothing. It's just black.
Ok. Let me know if you see
anything at all.
Are you doing it?
We're finished.
Why don't you wait outside
while I talk to your dad?
Wait with Miss Lucy.
Hey, wait.
It's fine.
Let me get this out of your eyes.
I don't know how you can see.
I can't see. That's why we're here. Duh.
Don't worry... the rolling of the eyes
and the attitude doesn't last for long.
10, 15 years, maybe.
It's just an act. She's scared.
It's not getting any better.
The decline has been accelerating
for the past few days.
The air's never been this bad.
They're gonna fix it, right?
Like always?
I hope so.
Hey. She's a 9-year-old girl.
What's she gonna do
with the rest of her life
blind in this place?
She's strong.
She shouldn't have to be.
Hey. You all right?
I just saw a little girl
with optic nerve damage
because of chronic oxygen deficiency.
She's going blind and I
can't do anything about it,
so, no, nothing about any of this is right.
You're doing what you can.
Why aren't you monitoring the radio?
Listening for Raven?
Have you looked outside? We're slammed.
It's still transmitting the automatic hail.
I'll take care of medical
and you listen to that radio.
Making contact with the ground
is the only way we can
really help these people.
Pod one, pod one, this
is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving, please respond.
Pod one, pod one, this
is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving, please respond.
One, pod one, this is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving...
Looks like everybody's up.
Did you guys see that?
You know it's from the
ark, right? It had to be.
Grab your stuff. Let's find out.
Bellamy said we're
gonna wait until sunrise.
Where is he?
Ever hear of knocking, bitch?
Oh, great, it's a free show.
Anyone else want to take a look?
Where the hell is Bellamy?
He took off a while ago.
Gear's gone.
He told everyone to stay.
Whatever's in that thing, he wants it.
We've gotta get there before he does.
You're welcome.
This isn't your fault, Clarke.
I should've known he'd go for that radio.
How are you supposed to
know something like that?
Because he's spent every
single minute since we landed
making sure no one
on The Ark finds out we're alive.
It doesn't mean you can predict
what people are gonna do.
That's exactly what I have to do.
I screwed up.
Let myself get distracted.
Bellamy!
What are you doing?
Go back to camp. It isn't safe.
You lied to everyone. You lied to me.
You just want whatever's in that pod...
Just go home!
You always want to play
the big brother, huh?
Well, guess what? Joke's on me.
You're just a selfish dick.
I did this for you, to protect you.
If The Ark finds out we're
alive, they'll come down.
And when they do...
I'm dead.
What did you do?
I shot him.
I shot Jaha.
What?
I found out they were sending you to Earth.
I couldn't let you go alone.
Someone came to me with a deal...
do this. Kill him,
and they'd get me on the dropship.
And I did it.
You killed the chancellor?
He floated our mother.
He locked you up.
He deserved it.
I didn't ask you to do that.
You're right.
I made the choice. This is on me.
Whatever they sent down,
I'll take care of it.
I didn't ask for any of this.
At 1930 hours,
all hatches and vents
leading to section 17 will be sealed.
It will appear to be a malfunction
of the fire containment system.
So, it'll look like an accident.
It's essential to maintaining public order
after the culling takes place.
All residents of Section 17
will be in their sleep period.
The council has already
issued a writ of consent
giving the chancellor
permission to carry out
the population reduction.
A sleep-inducing gas will be
introduced into the air.
On your command, the oxygen supply
to Section 17 will be cut off.
It should be painless.
Document needs your approval.
You have it...
with one alteration.
You'll give the order
to cut off the oxygen.
I don't have the authority.
In your capacity as chancellor.
Tonight, I will be in Section 17
inspecting repairs to the hull,
and when those doors are
closed on those people,
their fate will be my fate.
Your fate.
Don't do this.
My mind is made up.
I'm leaving you in terrible times, Marcus,
but you... you have a strength
that is not weakened by sentiment.
And that's exactly what it's going to
take for us to survive.
Pod one, pod one, this
is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving, please respond.
Pod one, pod one, this
is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving, please respond.
Pod one, pod one, this
is Ark Station Medical.
If you are receiving, please respond.
Should we split up?
- Yeah. You go that way.
- Ok.
- I'll check the bottom.
Ahh.
Crap. That's not good.
Oh, my God.
Hi.
I made it?
Ha!
Ahh. I dreamed it would smell like this.
Is this rain?
Welcome home.
Raven!
Finn!
I knew you couldn't be dead.
You're bleeding.
I don't care.
Ha ha!
How did you get here?
You know that big scrap hold,
the one on K deck?
You built that from scrap?
I kind of rebuilt it.
Please. Like that's hard.
It just needed a couple
parts and some love.
You're insane.
I'd do more for you and worse.
Just like you would for me.
Come on, sit down. Sit down here.
Let me get something for that.
I'm sorry.
Let's not talk about this.
We've known each other our whole lives.
We don't need to talk about it.
She needs to put pressure on her wound.
Thanks.
This is Clarke. She was
on the dropship, too.
Clarke?
This was all because of your mom.
My mom?
This was all her plan.
We were trying to come down here together.
If we waited... oh, my God.
We couldn't wait because
the council was voting
whether to kill 300 people to save air.
- When?
- Today.
We have to tell them you're alive.
The radio's gone.
It must've gotten loose during reentry.
I should've strapped it
to the A-strut. Stupid!
No, no, this is my fault.
Someone got here before us.
We have to find him.
Tell me it's not true.
Today there are so many things
that I wish weren't true.
Spare me the noble speech.
You know what I'm talking about.
You joining Section 17.
How could I ask anyone
to make a sacrifice that I'm not
willing to make myself?
So, you're gonna die peacefully
and leave humanity in the hands of Kane?
Chancellor Kane?
Yes. He won't hesitate to
do what needs to be done.
Thelonious, this is all happening too fast.
We've waited as long as possible.
There are things that
we can do to buy us time.
We should reconsider
forcing an algae bloom
to boost oxygen production.
You've read the studies. They would only
contaminate the water supply.
We can induce people into comas
to reduce their resource consumption.
We've gone through all the possibilities.
This is the only solution.
No, it can't be this.
I am doing what is right.
You're running away.
You think what you're doing is right
but you're a coward.
How are you gonna explain it to Wells?
How would you tell your son
that you let these people die
without doing absolutely everything
in your power to save them?
People of the Ark. My name is Jake Griffin.
I'm senior environmental engineer
and deputy resource officer.
Today, I need to talk
to you about our future.
Ok.
Hey!
Where is it?
Hey, princess. You taking
a walk in the woods?
They're getting ready to kill
300 people up there
to save oxygen.
And I can guarantee you
it won't be council members.
It'll be working people. Your people.
Bellamy. Where's the radio?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Bellamy Blake? They're
looking everywhere for you.
Shut up.
Looking for him why?
He shot Chancellor Jaha.
That's why you took the wristbands.
Needed everyone to think we're dead.
And all that "whatever the hell we want"?
You just care about saving your own skin.
Hey! Shooter! Where's my radio?
- Get out of my way.
- Where is it?
I should've killed you
when I had the chance.
Really? Well, I'm right here.
Where's my radio?
Ok, stop it.
Jaha deserved to die. You all know that.
Yeah, he's not my favorite person, either.
But he isn't dead.
What?
You're a lousy shot.
Bellamy, don't you see what this means?
You're not a murderer.
You always did what you had to do
to protect your sister.
That's who you are.
And you can do it again,
by protecting 300 of your people.
Where's the radio?
It's too late.
People of The Ark,
today I need to talk
to you about our future.
The things I need to tell you are serious.
Sir, have you been on the network?
No.
The Ark is dying. This city in space
that has been our sanctuary.
It's playing everywhere.
Tech's trying to shut it down.
We should never have
let her out of the cell.
Time is running out.
This is an undeniable reality,
but we have pledged our lives
to make sure that humanity
does not share that fate.
Now, while there is still time,
we must come together
and face this crisis head on.
I believe it will bring
out the best in us...
our strength, our humanity, our faith...
that we will come together
in this time of uncertainty.
My husband was killed
for trying to warn us.
In 12 hours, 320 people will be sacrificed
to extend our oxygen supply
unless we take action.
Dr. Abigail Griffin, open
this door immediately.
The future doesn't belong to
the chancellor or the council.
It belongs to all of us.
I should've told you about her.
It's ok.
I didn't think I'd see her again.
But you wouldn't take off your wristband.
You had hope. It's ok, I get it/
I was around, passably cute,
and now it's over.
Hey. I found it.
Can you fix it?
Maybe. But it'll take half a day
just to dry out the components
to see what's broken.
Like I said, it's too late.
Do you have any idea what you did?
Do you even care?
You asked me to help. I helped.
300 people are gonna
die today because of you.
Hold up. We don't have to talk to The Ark.
We just have to let them know
we're down here, right?
Yeah, but how do we do that with no radio?
You've taken an impossible situation
and made it worse.
This will cause a riot.
Good. Maybe we need one.
Guards are double-strengthen
and on alert station-wide.
I've posted riot teams in all public areas.
Any reports of unrest?
Not yet, but people are gathering.
There's a crowd of 400
strong right outside.
That's what you've done.
All we can do now is
determine our best option.
Options? We have no options.
We need time,
or everyone on this
station is going to die.
Either in an uprising or by suffocation.
Those are the options she's given us.
Sir. They sent an emissary
to speak with Abby.
All right.
The people outside are
sending someone in to talk.
To you.
His daughter's a patient of mine.
Hey, doc. I saw your video thing.
Crap news, it sounds like.
I'm sorry you had to hear it like that.
No good way to hear it, right?
Anyway... I'm here to
volunteer, I guess you'd call it.
Volunteer? For what?
Section 17, sir.
Any way you do the math,
some of us are gonna have to jump ship
if everyone's gonna make it, so...
I'm gonna jump.
You'd leave Reese without a father?
This morning, you told me
my daughter was going blind
and there was nothing
I could do to help her.
Turns out there is.
Count me in.
Chancellor, sir, I'll take a spot in 17.
Give my wife a little extra air.
Jake was right.
It would bring out the best in us.
We need to launch those flares ASAP
if we have any hope of saving those people.
Finn, get that control panel to camp.
You, pull out those firing circuits
in one piece or they won't work.
Clarke, can I have a hand?
Work these bolts here gently.
Rocket fuel likes to go boom.
We're going to need power to fire.
They're tying in the
batteries on the dropship.
Should be ready when we get there.
Great. So, what's the problem?
Nothing. I just...
Well, if we get the rockets to launch,
will they see them from The Ark?
Like the good book says,
it's all about burn time and cloud cover.
But I know your mom will be watching.
I've never seen anyone love
someone the way she loves you.
You know that, right?
I did.
It's complicated.
Here's the final list of volunteers.
They'll report to B deck
in less than an hour.
This is more than enough.
We rejected almost 100.
Essential personnel and minors.
Abby's announcement proved to be
very convincing.
I don't think that she or
her husband convinced anyone.
They spoke to something that
was already inside of them.
The new chancellor should remember that.
I better get to 17.
Don't want to be late for my own funeral.
Sir.
You don't need to do this now.
I know what I'm doing
is right for my people.
They've inspired me.
No, they volunteered
because you inspired them.
Jake Griffin inspired them
and I executed him.
I executed my friend.
One decision does not define a man.
Jake Griffin is gone. You're here.
Our survival depends on having a leader
who can inspire people to self-sacrifice.
You're that man.
Not me.
Why do you have to work the double shift?
It's not fair.
Sorry. Things need to get done.
You be good for Miss Lucy.
Thanks, because I was
gonna totally be terrible
if you didn't remind me.
- Come here.
- Stop it.
I can't even see your face.
Seriously.
Ok.
Just give me a kiss.
Hey.
I love you.
I love you, too.
All nonessential personnel,
please vacate Section 17.
Have we heard from Raven?
Move it, move it, move it!
You must vacate Section 17...
What changed his mind?
Just the truth.
I reminded him that
transitioning to a new chancellor
would be... destabilizing.
We can't afford any more upheaval.
No, we can't.
I left two men.
Monitoring the radio.
If there's any word from Raven,
they'll call down immediately.
I gave clear orders.
Thank you.
Mr. Lemkin, I want to thank
you for your sacrifice.
Don't. This is for my daughter.
You just think about doing right
for the people that are left behind.
Here you go.
Sir, all vents and hatchways
to Section 17 are closed.
We have a hard seal.
Sir?
The order?
And we hereby commit
these souls to the deep...
Who at their last gave all
to the world of the living.
May they be remembered forever,
until there is no more
pain, no more suffering,
and the abyss itself shall give up her dead
and return them to us.
You think they can see it from up there?
I don't know. I hope so.
Can you wish on this kind of shooting star?
Forget it.
I wouldn't even know what to wish for.
What about you?
You should sleep.
How?
We make the best choices that we can...
And then we put our
faith in a forgiving God.
Do you think we deserve to be forgiven?
Did you see that?
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -